100% pure adrenaline.
Point Break is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Kathryn Bigelow.
In Los Angeles, a gang of bank robbers who call themselves The Ex-Presidents commit
their crimes while wearing masks of Reagan, Carter, Nixon and Johnson.
Believing that the members of the gang could be surfers, the F.B.I.
sends young agent Johnny Utah to the beach undercover to
mix with the surfers and gather information.
Agent Johnny Utah, played by Keanu Reeves.
Bodhi / Mask President, played by Patrick Swayze.
Tyler Endicott, played by Lori Petty.
Agent Angelo Pappas, played by Gary Busey.
SAIC Ben Harp, played by John C. McGinley.
Roach, played by James LeGros.
Point Break is a 1991 American action film directed
by Kathryn Bigelow and written by W.
Peter Iliff.
It stars Patrick Swayze, Keanu Reeves, Lori Petty and Gary Busey.
The title refers to the surfing term "point break", where a wave breaks as
it hits a point of land jutting out from the coastline.
The film features Reeves as an undercover FBI agent who is tasked with investigating the identities of a
group of bank robbers while he develops a complex relationship with the group's leader (Swayze).
Development of Point Break began in 1986, when Iliff
wrote an initial script for the film.
Bigelow soon developed it with her husband, James Cameron,
and filming took place four years later.
It was shot across the western coast of the continental
United States and was budgeted at $24 million.
It was released on July 12, 1991.
Point Break opened to generally positive reviews, with critics
praising the chemistry between Reeves and Swayze.
During its theatrical run, it grossed over $83.5 million,
and has since gained a cult following.
A remake was released in 2015.
The film explores themes of surfing, surfer,
undercover agent, self-destruction, fbi.
The tone is intense.